

MIGUEL TRONCOSO GALDAMES
Full Stack - Developer

- +569 6450 9162
- Santiago, Chile.
- github.com/mtrunkbear
- in www.linkedin.com/in/miguel-troncoso-g

SKILLS

Technical skills:

JavaScript. HTML. CSS. ReactJs + Native. Next Js. Java. python. A. SQL (Postgre, Mysql). Strapi. Graph Ql. MongoDB. RESTful API CRUD. Solid Principles Cloud: Google Cloud, Firebase, AWS. EC2, S3, RDS, Vercel. Blockchain: Solidity and Java. Blockhain libraries: Ethers js, Web Js.

Econometric Analysis. Business Analytics. Quantitative Finance. Mendeley. Latex. Excel.

Soft skills:

Adaptation and capacity for independent work. Empathy. Emotional Intelligence. Dedication. Building relationships with clients. Collaboration. Tolerance. Conflict resolution. Leadership.

Language:

Intermediate English B2 - Native Spanish.

COURSES

- Data Science for Business
 Diego Portales University
- Statistics (I, II) Finance (I, II and III) Econometrics
 Diego Portales University
- Intermediate Python DataCamp
- Javascript course
 Platzi
- Bitcoin and Blockchain Course

EDUCATION

Master Digital Business.
 Diego Portales University
 2022-2022

Commercial Engineering Mention Economics.
 Diego Portales University
 2017-2021

ABOUT ME

I am a professional with an entrepreneurial spirit and openness to innovation, I am deeply curious about new information technologies, that is, Data Science, Blockchain and Fintech. I have a self-taught profile with autonomy and proactivity in research and problem solving. I consider myself qualified for decision making and strategic thinking, due to my technical experience and soft skills related to entrepreneurship and information technology management. My passion is business, economics and technology. I think that creativity and efficiency make business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul-2022 - May 2022 (11 months), Fullstack OPIS Developer

- · I participated in the complete development of a web application using agile methodologies.
- The app included SaaS solutions, management dashboards and tools, and used Blockchain and DLT technologies for token ledger.
- I worked with various backend and frontend technologies and libraries, such as React, Next.js, Node.js, Strapi, MongoDB, SQL, GraphQL and Git. I also developed Smart Contracts and NFT's using Solidity and web3.js.
- · Cloud services such as Firebase, Google Places, Vercel, AWS EC2, S3, RDS were used.
- In addition to planning, suggesting the technology stack and implementing it, a lot of emphasis was placed on the quality and cleanliness of the code.
- · Various aspects of the app's performance were improved which substantially improved the UX/UI.
- It was a very complete task since it not only included development tasks but also planning and business strategy.

Jul-2022 - May 2022 (11 months), Fullstack Developer DREAMBOX

- Participation in proof of concept projects for clients from different sectors, particularly during the
 months of July and December for clients from the banking sector to identify the most appropriate one
 for the case and develop a solution from scratch that would demonstrate the usefulness of the technology.
- I used my research skills to analyze the different blockchain and DLT technologies, eventually we selected Quorum.
- Corda, Hedera, Fuction(x) and Polygon Edge, among others, were also investigated to develop the solution.
- Blockchain nodes were built under different cloud infrastructures such as Google Cloud CE.
- I've worked with languages like Java, Node.js, Solidity, and React.js to create smart-contracts, and I've used libraries like Web3js, Ethers js, and Corda Core to interact with the blockchain.
- As one of the lead developers of the solution, I worked collaboratively with other developers to implement blockchain technology in the project and demonstrate the usefulness of the technology to the client. The results of the project were very successful and we received excellent feedback from the client.

Feb 2022 – Jul 2022 (5 months) Internship Front-End Developer APPROVECHA

- In my work I worked with a team in the development of two mobile applications based on React Native which included:
- Participation in the transpilation of an App based on React Native from JavaScript to Typescript, using support libraries.
- Responsive programming and user interface design, which meant a significant improvement for a wide range of resolutions. (React Native, Node JS and CSS).
- Improvement in the interface and standardization of the styling of components.
- Enrichment in the functionalities and structure of the code.
- · Research and installation of new resources.
- Solving technical problems and errors in the components, given different causes such as bundling errors, visual errors, dependency management and environment errors, knowledge of Npm, Gradle, handling of Node js, Javascript and Java was necessary.